

# **Marius Daniel Sima**

**Junior Frontend Developer - Freelancer**Arad

# **Contact details**

Email: simamarius1331@gmail.com

Tel: +40753020568

City: Arad

# About me

Junior Frontend Developer with experience working on projects across(Transport, Automotive, Construction, Hospitality) industries. I was using the React JS library on two of the projects I was developing. I gained a lot of knowledge regarding Frontend development at the time I was taking the courses from Scrimba, Great Learning and Youtube tutorials, where I learned: Html, CSS, JS, React, Bootstrap, and Figma.

During my journey of becoming a Frontend Developer, I was fortunate enough to be guided by a senior Full Stack Developer and also took some private lessons. I am familiar with Git commands and GitHub repositories.

#### My skills:

- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- React Is
- Git
- Github
- Figma

Willing to start immediately as an Junior Frontend / intern and be remote For projects contact:

Email: simamarius1331@gmail.com

# **Professional experience**

Experience by departments

IT Software: 1 year and 11 months

Transportation / Distribution: 6 years

Sales: 3 years and 4 months

Aug 2021 - present

Junior Frontend Developer - Freelancer

1 year and 11 months

Remote (from home) | IT Software | IT / Telecom

Make websites for clients from Transport, Automotive, Construction, Hospitality

industries.

Acquired skills and competencies:

HTML, JavaScript, CSS, CSS3, GIT, HTML5, Bootstrap, Node JS, ReactJS

Jul 2017 - present Admin - SIMA TRANS LOGISTICS SRL

6 years Arad | Transportation / Distribution | Auto / Automotive

Made and maintained a website for this company.

I have a transport manager certificate in this field of activity plus an initial CPI

professional attestation certificate (professional car driver)

Acquired skills and competencies:

HTML, CSS, Auto, transport logistics, car transport

Feb 2020 - May 2023 Co-Founder - DD LEASING CORPORATION SRL

3 years and 4 months Arad | Sales | Auto / Automotive

Car sales consultancy, leasing consultant for Banca Transilvania, Unicredit Leasing

and other leasing partners.

Made and maintained two websites for this company

Acquired skills and competencies:

Windows, CSS, JS, HTML5, Desktop, smartbill, microso office, car rent, Oblio, bank

contracts

Dec 2022 - Feb 2023 Sales advisor - Ford - CARBENTA COM SRL

3 months Arad | Sales | Auto / Automotive

Acquired skills and competencies:

CRM, microsoft outlook, Sales, crm customer relationship management, contract

negotiation, Negotiation

**Education** 

2012 - 2015 Undergraduate - Vasile Goldis Arad, Arad

University of Medicine, Pharmacy and Dentistry | Arad

2008 - 2012 High School / Vocational school - Pedagogic High School Dimitrie

**Tichindeal Arad** 

Mathematical - Informatics | Arad

# **Skills**

# **General skills**

HTML5, CSS3, JS, ecdl diploma, Microsoft Windows 10, microsoft office microsoft word, Google Chrome, Gmail, Yahoo Mail, transport planning, manager transport, professional car driver

# **Foreign languages**

Romanian: Advanced

**English:** Intermediate

# Other sections

#### **Cerifications**

## **Certificate of completion**

date acquired Dec 2022

I admitted the CSS online course from Greate Learing Academy ,but now I follow the course from SCRIMBA, "THE FRONTEND PATH", I'm learning and I do some projects that include HTML, CSS and JS.

## **Certificate of professional driver training**

date acquired Jul 2020

#### **Cargo Transport Manager Certificate**

date acquired Nov 2019

# **Dental Technician License**

date acquired Jul 2015

# **ECDL Digital Competent**

date acquired Mar 2012

#### **Hobbies**

# basketball,Fitness,swimming,Tennis,Ping-pong,Cycling,WEB developer,PSP

#### **Projects**

#### Rent a car App

period Jun 2023 - Jun 2023

I created this web application for the company DD LEASING CORPORATION SRL, in which I was the founder, to generate the rent contracts and the minutes of receipt and takeover, the contracts are generated in PDF with the Print button, also for version 2 which is not public but only for this company, I also added a database with Firebase, with client addition in the database and with data retrieval and auto-completion in the inputs if the client exists in the database by his name.

#### **Build Masters React**

period May 2023 - May 2023

This website was created in React, which contains 5 components for the landing page component, in the services component there is a component that contains all the data that will be used as props to render a templated component for each individual service. The website is responsive for desktop, laptop, tablet and phone.

#### **Units Convertor**

period Feb 2023 - Feb 2023

I created this website to practice algorithmic functions. The website is responsive for desktop, laptop, tablet and phone.

#### **Football Scoreboard**

period Nov 2022 - Nov 2022

I did this project for beginners at the Scrimba course, to learn JS functions, how to

target an element by its id and then change its value after calling the corresponding increment function for each button: + 1,+2,+3 and a function for the button: New Game to reset the values to 0.

#### **Calculator**

period Nov 2022 - Nov 2022

I did this beginner project to practice more JS functions, how to target an element by its id, how to change the value from result input. I add the button LR to show the last result. In calculate function if the result is not an integer to round the result to a maximum of 5 decimal places

## **DD Leasing**

period Jul 2022 - Jul 2022

This website was created with bootstrap template for the company DD Leasing Corporation SRL from Arad, Romania.

#### **Portfolio**

period Feb 2022 - Feb 2022

Portfolio created with my projects, I update it when I add another project to this portfolio

# **Driving license**

## **Category B**

date acquired 21 Jul 2011

# **Category C**

date acquired 11 Nov 2011

#### **Category E**

date acquired 07 Mar 2012